military1.com 2014-11-21

# Military1 - Privacy Policy

This Web site is owned and operated by:

Praetorian Digital  
200 Green St., Suite 200  
San Francisco, CA 94111

We are committed to maintaining your confidence and trust with respect to the information we collect from you. This privacy policy applies to [www.Military1.com](http://www.firerescue1.com/) (“Military1”) and sets forth what information we collect about you, how we use your information, and the choices you have about how we use your information.

Military1 is dedicated to safeguarding your privacy online. As a policy, we will not sell, share or otherwise misuse your customer information. Your customer information helps us customize Military1 to your interests and allows us to negotiate valuable member discounts and related services. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our many offerings.

This privacy policy was last updated on 02/07/2014.

**What personally identifiable information does Military1 collect from me?**

Military1 collects information in several ways from different parts of our network of web sites.

Some personal information is gathered when you register. During registration, Military1 asks all users for your name, email address, city, occupation, industry and personal interests. To confirm the identity of military personnel, we also ask for agency information. The more information you volunteer (and the more accurate it is), the better we are able to customize your experience. Once you register you are no longer anonymous to Military1 - you will select an appropriate Military1 username, and are then given access to Military1's many offerings

In addition to registration we may ask you for personal information at other times, including (but not limited to) when you enter a sweepstakes, contest or promotion sponsored by Military1 and/or our many partners; when you post a Military1 Classified ad; when you submit a listing for a web site; and when you report a problem with one of our sites or services. If you contact Military1 we may keep a record of that correspondence. Military1 also occasionally asks users to complete surveys that we use for research purposes. Wherever Military1 collects personal information we include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page.

**What are cookies and how does Military1 use them?**

As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, Military1 uses cookies to store and sometimes track information about you. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. All areas on Military1 where you are prompted to log-in or that are customizable require that you accept

Generally, we use cookies to:

  * (1) Remind us of who you are and to access your account information (stored on our computers) in order to deliver to you a better and more personalized service. This cookie is set when you register or "Sign In" and is modified when you "Sign Out" of our services. The three most common pieces of personal information stored by our cookies are your username, password and security level. This is to verify your permissions to view secure areas of the site and provide a personalized experience upon sign in. Other submitted personal information such as rank and city are not linked to cookies.
  * (2) Estimate our audience size. Each browser accessing Military1 is given a unique cookie which is then used to determine the extent of repeat usage, usage by a registered user versus by an unregistered user, and to help target advertisements based on user interests and behaviour.
  * (3) Track your progress and number of entries in some of our promotions, sweepstakes and contests. When a Military1-hosted promotion uses cookies, the information written to the cookie indicates the player's progress through the promotion, and may be used to track entries, submissions, and status in prize drawings
  * (4) Measure certain traffic patterns, which areas of Military1's network of web sites you have visited, and your visiting patterns in the aggregate. We use this research to understand how our users' habits are similar or different from one another so that we can make each new experience on Military1 a better one. We may use this information to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that you and other users will see on our sites.

Advertising networks that serve ads onto Military1 may also use their own cookies. Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Military1.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any of these third parties. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences.truste.com/).  Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to use those Military1 services that require registration in order to participate.

Military1 also collects IP addresses for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. In addition, Military1 Mail includes IP addresses in outgoing mail message headers.

Our tracking technology used for client campaigns throughout the site does not collect any personal identifiable information that you provide as a part of your Military1 membership. Your personal information stored in cookies is only used for the purposes listed above to help improve your user experience.

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)**

Our third party advertising partners may employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective.  Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users.  In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information.

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients.  This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.  If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see “Choice and Opt-out.”

**How does Military1 use my information?**

Military1's primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you, the user, with a customized experience on our network of sites. This includes personalization services, interactive communications and many other types of services, most of which are completely free to you. In order to provide services free of charge, we display advertisements. By knowing a little about you, Military1 is able to deliver more relevant advertisements and content, and hence better service, to you.

In our role of delivering targeted advertisements, Military1 plays the middleman. Advertisers give us an advertisement and tell us the type of audience they want to reach (for example, active military personnel). Military1 takes the advertisement and displays it to users meeting those criteria. In this process, the advertiser never has access to individual account information. Only Military1 has access to individuals' accounts. This kind of advertisement targeting is done with banner ads.

Military1 does research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior based on the information provided to us upon registration, during a promotion, from our server log files or from surveys. We do this to better understand and serve our users. This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis. Military1 may share this aggregated data with advertisers or business partners.

**Who is collecting information?**

When you are on Military1 and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Military1 alone, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. In rare other cases we may offer other co-branded sites the ability to keep areas of their site behind closed doors for users who are NOT verified by our database as an active military personnel. In order to provide this co-branded service to you, it is necessary for us to share your username and security level with our partner company. This information is stored within a cookie during login and not otherwise collected by the partner company for any purpose. If data is being collected and/or maintained by any company other than Military1, you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service. Our privacy policy does apply to the information collected on these co-branded sites.  You should read the privacy statement of our co-branded partner. If you have any questions about the use of your information by co-branded sites or experience login problems on a co-branded site please email [support@Military1.com.](mailto:support@Military1.com)

Promotions that run on Military1 may be sponsored by companies other than Military1 or may be cosponsored by Military1 and another company. Some or all data collected during a promotion may be shared with the sponsor. If data will be shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. You can decide not to participate in the promotion if you don't want your data to be shared.

Please be aware that Military1 advertisers or web sites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. The information practices of those web sites linked to Military1 are not covered by this privacy statement.

**With whom does Military1 share my information?**

As a general rule, Military1 will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. Please see the Terms of Service or Use Agreements for each of our products and services for more detailed information about how your personal information may be shared. The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed.

Business Partners & Sponsors: Military1 may disclose your personal information to business partners or sponsors, but this is specifically described to you prior to data collection or prior to transferring the data. Details of shared use can be found in specific Terms of Service or Use Agreements, and sweepstakes and promotions rules. Some or all data collected during a Military1 promotion may be shared with a sponsor. If personally identifying data about you will be shared, we will tell you before we collect or transfer the data.

Many promotions offer opportunities to request additional information from sponsors. By requesting more information, you give Military1 permission to transfer your personal information to the sponsor so they can fulfill your request. In many instances, only your email address will be shared. If more information will be shared with the sponsor, you will be notified prior to the transfer.

Merchants listed on Military1 have separate privacy and data collection practices. Military1 has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies. For more information regarding the merchant, their store, and their privacy policies, return to that store's home page and click on their Information link.

From time to time, you may be offered the opportunity to receive materials or special offers from third parties. If you opt-in to receive information from these third parties, Military1 will (with your permission) share your name and email address with them. If you wish to no longer receive materials from these third parties, please contact them directly.

Third Party Data & Data in the Aggregate: Under confidentiality agreements, Military1 may match user information with third party data. Also, Military1 discloses aggregated user statistics in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.

**Disclosure of Personal Information to Third Parties**

Access to your personal information is restricted to our employees, agents, representatives and service providers and entities for whom we are acting as an agent, licensee or publisher, such as societies and our affiliated group companies, for the purposes set forth above. Service providers are only allowed to use your personal information _only as necessary to provide_ these services to us.

With your consent, we also may share your personal information with our affiliated group companies and/or with non-affiliated third parties that wish to send you information about their products and services that may be of interest to you, and users who have consented to receive such information may receive communications from these third parties.

We will not otherwise disclose any personal information without your consent except under the following circumstances:

\- In response to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our rights to defend against legal claims;

\- If we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, safety of person or property, violation of our policies, or as otherwise required by law; and

\- If Military1, a related asset or line of business is acquired by, transferred to or merged with another company, in which case, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

**What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?**

Military1 may, from time to time, send you email regarding our products and services. In addition, if you indicated upon registration that you are interested in receiving offers or information from Military1 and our partners, we may occasionally send you direct mail about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you. Only Military1 (or agents working on behalf of Military1 and under confidentiality agreements) will send you these direct mailings and only if you indicated that you do not object to these offers. If you do not want to receive such mailings, simply tell us when you give us your personal information. Or, at any time you can easily edit your Military1 Account Information to no longer receive such offers and mailings. You will need your Military1 ID and Password in order to access your Military1 Account Information.

On some types of Military1 promotions, we will ask for your email address in order to update you on your score, entries, and status in prize drawings. When you participate in these types of promotions, you automatically receive promotion-related email, unless you choose the no-email option that some promotions offer. Occasionally these promotion-related email messages may include targeted advertisements.

Military1 does not sell, share or rent user information to anyone. We will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting the transfer. If you do not wish to allow your data to be shared, you can choose not to use a particular service or not to participate in certain promotions or contests.

**What is Military1's policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personally identifiable information?**

You may edit, update or delete your Military1 Account Information and your public Military1 Profile at any time by using your Military1 ID and password. If you have forgotten your password, please click here to request a new password. For all other problems signing in to Military1, please [contact us](mailto:support@Military1.com).

Your Military1 account can be deleted or deactivated, but doing so will result in not being able to access any members-only area of the Military1 network. If you saved the confirmation email you received when you first created your Military1 account, you can use the URL provided in that message to delete your account at any time. Please contact [support@Military1.com](mailto:support@Military1.com) for further instructions about deleting or deactivating your Military1 account.

If you are participating in a Military1 promotion and you wish to update your email address on the promotions mailing list or to quit a promotion and cease receiving promotion-related email, please contact [support@Military1.com](mailto:support@Military1.com).

Knowing that you use certain services or features may help us to offer you better and more relevant content and advertisements. But as with all personally identifiable information, we do not make this available to any third parties without your permission. Any user statistics that we may provide to prospective advertisers or partners regarding financial product or service usage on Military1 are provided in the aggregate only and do not include any personally identifiable information about any individual user.

**Data Retention**

We retain the personal information we collect from you for as long as the information is relevant to our business purposes or until you request that we remove the data by contacting Praetorian Digital below. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Unsubscribing and opting out of personally identifiable information**

Your username may be displayed when submitting member comments to any video on Military1. Your email address will only be used for us to send you materials that you have subscribed to in the past. We provide you the opportunity to opt-out; of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes when we ask for this information

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter or other promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each communication or by emailing [support@Military1.com](mailto:support@Military1.com).

You will be notified when your personal information is collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.

**Tell a Friend**

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. This feature is available with Military1 videos throughout Military1.com. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Military1 does not store this information and will not send any additional messages to the referred user.

**Public Forums**

We use other third parties to provide forums on Military1.com. When you sign up for a Military1 member account, we will share your username as necessary for the forums application to provide that service. If you use a bulletin board, blog, or forum on this Web site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose than listed above. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at customersupport@Military1.com.  In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

**What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?**

Your Military1 Profile is password-protected so that you and only you have access to this personal information. You may edit your Military1 Account Information and Military1 Profile by using your Military1 ID and password.

We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Military1 will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited email. Also remember to sign out of your Military1 account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Military1 cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

**What security precautions are in place to protect the identity and security of military personnel on Military1?**

Military1 has taken several precautions to protect the identity, account names and passwords of officers when they register and log on to Military1.com. Unfortunately, this process cannot be 100% secure and Military1 is not responsible for the misuse of these user names and passwords. Despite all of our precautions, you use Military1 at your own risk.

**Testimonials**

We periodically post member testimonials on Military1 which may contain personally identifiable information such as the member's username. We do obtain the member's consent prior to posting each testimonial. If you have any questions regarding testimonials on Military1 or would like a testimonial that includes your personal information removed please [contact us](mailto:support@Military1.com).

**Social Media Widgets**

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Changes in this Privacy Statement**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective.

If you ever have questions regarding the Military1 privacy policy please email [support@Military1.com](mailto:support@Military1.com).

_________________________________________________________________________________________________________________________

_Military1 has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal.?_

_If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe[here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request)._

* * *
